hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast I
talk about how coaches mentors and
trainers can scale their businesses to
make more money online and reach the
kind of clients that they want now today
I want to talk about how to run an
exceptional group coaching program I've
been teaching this to my clients for the
last year and I've been running group
coaching programs for nearly a decade
with a ton of success in fact I don't
recommend that people do one-on-one
coaching as their main business model
that you reserve one-on-one
VIP type coaching for only a select few
of the people that you work with and so
here's the thing a lot of coaches go
into the coaching industry with
codependency based mindset where they
want
to help other people which is a good
thing but they put their identity around
how many people they can help and what
they can do to help people with that
okay they're not thinking as a business
owner for me we have built multiple
coaching and Consulting business
businesses that have scaled to tens of
millions of dollars not because we don't
serve our clients but because we put
business models in place that allow us
to not have to work ourselves to death
that don't that we don't need to do
one-on-one calls trading dollars for
hours but we're able to serve a group as
a whole at a high level I'll tell you
this when you're doing group coaching
one of the differences is that you're
not serving tons of different wide range
of people you're serving a very select
specific group of people and you're
learning how to attract that very
specific group of people in front of you
and help deliver a specific result now
one of the mistakes that a lot of people
make again when they get into coaching
is that they're so focused on their
identity being tied to delivering
results to people I hear it all the time
from people I'm not going to build a
business if I can't deliver results I
get it again sounds great but the truth
is is that you are not the one
responsible for the client getting
result I'm going to say that
again and don't misinterpret it in some
way that you think I said based on
something I never said I did not say
that you don't deliver client results I
say that your responsibility is not the
client's
results the result is the responsibility
of the client themselves by doing the
work in their business your
responsibility is to create systems and
training and processes that can pull the
best out of them so that they can learn
how to do that and so number one we got
to break up with this codependent way of
thinking if we want to be a successful
business owner that it's our
responsibility to make sure come hell or
high water I get everybody a result no
it's not even a reality and I have
worked with thousands of coaches and the
ones that have that thinking they're
broke they don't make any money because
they're TI
B basically killing themselves with
energy to others
results and that's not a way to build a
business that's not a way to run a
family that's not a way to
be a
human and what codependency is is where
we literally kill ourselves for somebody
else we sacrifice ourselves for some
body else's
result so boundaries are important and
you might be listening to me right now
and you might disagree with what I'm
saying that's okay can I tell you this
that that's no way to successfully build
a business what a business is is you get
very specific about what you can do at
scale to reach people and you still
deliver results that way at scale okay
and so that's where group coaching comes
in and the way that you deliver
exceptional group coaching is number one
by accepting that yes it's less
interaction than oneon-one yes you're
not connecting with the same people at
the same level but number two it's a far
more profitable leveraged business model
because you're not attaching your
time to the dollars that you make you're
not tying your identity to the results
that you
deliver and that's one of the number one
things that you have to have to
understand and yes we deliver results
yes we create excellent courses yes we
create incredible support and
accountability I'm not negating any of
that but I'm saying that you got to
release the pressure
and mental destruction that we put on
ourselves to have to strive so hard and
work so hard to deliver the results to
clients I meet people all the time and
they do this
and the like group coaching is not for
me because I just I just couldn't
deliver the kind of results
that I feel I need to do to attach my
name to with group coaching and they are
choosing to make less money to not
actually have a business to have
something that is inferior both for
themselves and ultimately for the
clients and the impact they want to have
when their idea is to have impact they
are limiting themselves by focusing so
much on
individual
impact and less on actually building a
sustainable business that reaches a
wider range of people so number one You'
got to choose if you're doing group
coaching you have to choose that your
revenue is important the kind of that
the amount of money that you're making
is important and you might say this well
that that's putting profit over people
no it's not it's not at all
because you're able to help more people
by doing group coaching and you're able
to reach more people and you're able to
leverage your time to impact more people
at that level so you have to literally
give
up the need inside of
you that again this is the first stage
with group coaching that you have to do
that I have to be the one that is
responsible for everybody's result
as far as that goes
individually and then you have to create
systems that can impact people at scale
and the way that these systems work are
we can use coaching groups whether it be
a Facebook group or a school Community
where you can have people ask questions
in the group you know we use this in my
accelerator program where people can ask
questions in a Facebook group and I can
answer those throughout the week I go in
there and I respond to the questions
people leave you can do this on a
Discord
Channel and you can host live coaching
calls live group coaching calls in a
group setting with
people where you can interact with the
group on a live Zoom call and you can
answer questions now again you might be
saying but that's I'm not able to
deliver results to 100% of all the
people by doing see you got to really
like resolve that thing and learn to let
go of other people's choices
over their
lives and learn how to lead a group of
people by learning how to lead a group
of people this is like what a setting in
a university does where you are somebody
who is talking to a group of people and
they are interacting with you through
verbal interaction through written
interaction and they're able to take
your message which is a on to many model
and you're able to communicate to
multitudes of people to help deliver the
results that they
expect and so for you to be able to
build a business at scale you have to
learn to accept the one to many models
limitations and then utilize the very
best framework of what actually delivers
results in a on to many model you're
able to
leverage live Zoom calls you're able to
leverage recorded classes and courses
that answer questions that people have
you're able to facilitate live Q&A
interaction with your audience with the
people that you're looking to interact
with you're able to get them to ask
questions consistently of you so that
then by asking those questions they're
able to get the answers and the
solutions that they're looking
for and so then what you do is you're
able to figure out okay what does the
group as a whole what are they dealing
with the
most what are they wanting a solution to
the most the group as a
whole starts to deal with similar
problems similar frustrations and so
your goal is to pay attention to what is
the group as a whole asking about what
are the questions that the entire group
is dealing with that they're wanting
answers
to and so this person over here might
ask a question this person over here
might ask a question and you're able to
bring those questions together and find
what is the common thread across all of
those and now all of our marketing
materials are used to draw in people
that have these similar and common
issues and so you're able to serve this
group as a whole by getting very very
specific to a few issues and not trying
to serve dozens and dozens and dozens of
issues with people and so you're able to
create courses on these these problems
that they're dealing with and you're
able to create Frameworks on these
issues and by doing that then you're
able to lead people with your marketing
material into a very specific place
where you're able to get them results
quickly okay and so by you being able to
do that by you you being able to
communicate powerfully with a group of
people by learning how to communicate
that
means putting yourself into a position
of authority in the group where people
are looking up to you where people are
looking to you as somebody that they can
respect that they want to listen to that
they want to lean forward with and
engage with you're able to provide value
to that
group and teach them and Mentor them and
Coach them and provide them with the
support the accountability that they're
looking for and the answers that are
going to solve the problems that they
have and so this the type of systems
that we like to use is having some kind
of group interaction and a schedule you
have a very specific scheduled time one
day a week twice a week you could do
every day I have know clients that do
one call every day and what it is is
these are boundaries that people know
that Within These bound boundaries is
how they're able to engage with you is
how they're able to interact they can
show up on a live call they can show up
in a group interactive setting to be
able to get the help the support the
accountability that they're looking for
now is everybody going to be served in
this no because literally there are
people who are going to choose to not
show up they're going to choose to not
go through the training they're going to
choose to not interact and so you got to
learn to release the codependent control
that you're trying to have over other
people doing what they should but learn
at the same time how to be assertive at
leading people at scale by telling
people
expectations what you require of them
what you expect of them how you expect
them to show up how you expect that
interaction to
go and then when you do this people will
follow what you're saying and so it
starts with you having confidence in how
you're communicating believing that this
process works I can tell you this we've
built multiple businesses in this space
and this process works extremely well to
be able to reach people to be able to
create businesses that generate millions
of dollars in
revenue and I think it'll work for you
as well if you are a coach if you are a
trainer if you are a mentor it's time to
step over the threshold of oh I got to
serve all these individual people and I
have I help such a wide range of people
and start to get more specific as to the
ones that you can deliver results to the
fastest so who are the ones that engage
with you the most that you can deliver
the fastest result
to and that actually show up with you
asking questions and leaning forward and
actually interacting in a way where they
want to get the result where they're
actually showing up on the calls not
everybody's going to show up on your
group calls but when you can pay
attention to who are the ones that are
showing up who are the ones that are
actually
engaging you might have to answer
questions that you don't always want to
ask maybe you've already answered it
before but can I tell you
this that doesn't mean that you're a bad
coach it means that you've actually
dialed in your coaching well if people
are asking the same question over and
over and over again and then you can
have resources that you can direct
people to to get those answers that
they're
seeking and so if you're a coach if
you're a mentor if you're a trainer and
you're looking how do I shift into this
group coaching
world you're selling a result you're
selling an outcome you're selling a
solution to people but you're not taking
hours and hours and hours of your time
to deliver it you create a system that
contains courses it contains the ability
for people to contact you in the group
so that the entire group sees all the
questions you create calls where people
can ask questions and yes will there
people who slip through the cracks of
course you need to accept that fact
will there be people who feel like they
weren't served at the highest level by
your group yes and you have to accept
that fact but when you can learn and the
number one skill that it takes to really
do this well is to communicate well when
you can learn how to be a master
Communicator with your group and this is
what I Mentor people on in my coaching
Community is how to communicate well how
to deliver the results that they they
promised to people how to Market to
people well how to bring people into
their ecosystem and actually create the
kind of environment that's going to
deliver to the those clients when you
can do this you can learn to lead at
scale and you can learn how to
communicate your value to people to get
them to take
action and you learn how to motivate
people in the right way it's about being
assertive not passive you're not waiting
for people to come to you with their
questions but rather you're somebody who
provides the opportunity and then you
directly give people the solution that
they're looking for when you can learn
to do that you can Master this game of
group coaching and group consulting at
scale and so I believe that you can do
it I know that you can there's a lot of
great coaches that are out there that
they they've they've crushed it at
one-on-one coaching that when they
transition to group coaching yes is it a
bit of a hurdle that they need to jump
past yes is there a bit of a struggle
that they're feeling like oh I'm not
sure if this is exactly how I want to do
it oh I'm not sure if I'm able to
deliver this at the way that I want to
oh I'm not sure if I'm able to show up
the way that I really want to in my
business but when they learn to accept
those
limitations and they learn to say okay
I'm going to show up and I'm going to
interact with
people and I'm going to learn and I'm
going to and I'm going to
choose to give it my best with these
people that are asking for my
help you're able to deliver results and
create a business that's able to create
the kind of money that you want to make
if you want to act create the kind of
income that you want to make group
coaching you you need to do it
one-on-one coaching is not going to make
you the kind of money you want to make
it's going to burn you
out and you're plateaued and you're
limited as to how far you can go and so
the solution is to say okay I'm going to
give up a lot of the benefits that there
might be to one-on-one coaching and I'm
going to choose to put this into a very
specific Niche a very specific idea that
I'm going to help a group with and I'm
going to build an audience of people
that I can help interact with a group
on and then I'm going to show up each
day and I'm going to deliver results to
those people and I'm going to help those
people get the result that they expect
from me and so when you can learn to do
this you can have the kind of business
that you want and the kind of results
that people are looking forward to
paying you for all right it's not rocket
science but it does take some courage it
does take defeating the fear and the
worry and the doubts and the
insecurities that we might have that are
telling us oh I'm not ready yet or oh
I'm not sure if people are going to want
to listen to me like this you know it's
comfortable to stay in one1 coaching
it's easy to stay in one1 coaching
because you're not risking anything
you're not risking putting yourself out
there and then the group rejecting you
as far as that goes there's a lot that
you got to deal with mentally when it
comes to doing this but the fastest way
to do it is to just rip that Band-Aid
off and do it even if you feel
uncomfortable even if it's scary even if
you're worried that it's not going to
work out
perfectly and then start to watch the
seeds of those things start to fall into
place for you in a positive way all
right listen this has been the grow Your
Life podcast stay plugged in plug in on
my YouTube channel subscribe we'll see
you in the next episode
[Applause]
[Music]